# Graeme Thornber

Mobile: +6421 0292 4529

E-mail Address: <a href="mailto:gdthornber@gmail.com">gdthornber@gmail.com</a>
Website: <a href="mailto:www.graemethornber.com">www.graemethornber.com</a>

### **Profile**

I'm a Kiwi Web Developer with a firm arsenal of skills in all aspects of building and maintaining modern web applications. With over a decade of experience in the web industry, I've worked with several digital agencies in Auckland, Wellington and Bonn, Germany.

I specialize in building rich, cross-platform and cross-browser user experiences with typical front-end technologies: HTML5, CSS3 and Javascript and jQuery. These skills are complimented with a solid background in pHp & mySQL, engineer-level knowledge of open-source CMS platforms Wordpress and Drupal, and an expanding knowledge of Swift, AngularJS, React and many other libraries and frameworks.

Super-fast at prototyping and capable of incredible concentration in programming, I love problem-solving, delving into impossible tasks, and providing excellent solutions to the myriad of obstacles regularly presented in the web industry.

I stand out amongst other developers due to my social nature and ease of dealing professionally and personally with people of varying cultures and customs. I also have a very keen eye for UX and strong skills in editing and copywriting.

My favourite things to do outside of work are playing guitar, cooking, fishing, swimming, hiking, gardening and the occasional gaming. I also speak German and love travelling.

### Education

2005 – 2006 Natcoll (now Youbee) in Auckland, New Zealand

Diploma in Web Development

1992 – 1996 Howick College, Auckland, New Zealand

English, Computer Studies, Drama, Music, Japanese

## **Employment History**

2016 - present

**Lead Developer -** Spitfire: The Digital Agency (Auckland, NZ) <u>www.spitfire.co.nz</u> Managing contract developers and working across many different projects and platforms: Concrete5, pHp, HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, SASS, Git, Grunt, Capistrano, AWS. Recent sites: <u>www.roche.co.nz</u>, <u>www.cancerinfo.co.nz</u>, <u>www.chelsea.co.nz</u>

2014 - 2015

Senior Freelance Developer (Auckland, NZ) <a href="www.graemethornber.com">www.graemethornber.com</a>
Working with a variety of different technology stacks for mostly digital agencies including: <a href="Colenso BBDO">Colenso BBDO</a>, <a href="RAPP">RAPP</a> (DDB)</a>, <a href="Image Center Group">Image Center Group</a>, <a href="image DesignMedia">iDesignMedia</a>, <a href="Insight Creative">Insight Creative</a>, <a href="J. Walter Thompson">J. Walter Thompson</a>, <a href="Satellite Media">Satellite Media</a>, <a href="Touchcast">Touchcast</a>.

2011 - 2013

**Senior PHP Developer** - Scopevisio AG (Bonn, Germany) - <a href="www.scopevisio.com">www.scopevisio.com</a> At Scopevisio I built and maintained the company's website in Drupal using Web Services with REST, SOAP, JSON and XML while also gaining an advanced knowledge of SEO.

2010 - 2011

**Lead Developer / Project Manager** - +The Church+ (Wellington, NZ) - <u>www.thechurch.co.nz</u> Building custom Wordpress themes and plugins for local and international clients, I took sole ownership of many projects - from initial scoping and architecture to building, deploying and maintaining bespoke content-management driven web applications.

2008 - 2010

**Front End Developer** - Solutionists (Auckland, NZ) - <a href="www.solutionists.co.nz">www.solutionists.co.nz</a>
During my time at Solutionists I worked on over 100 projects: from building table-based HTML4 email templates to brochure campaigns and full corporate E-Commerce solutions.

2007 - 2008

Freelance Developer (Auckland, NZ) - www.graemethornber.com

After completing my Diploma in 2006 I made the transition from hospitality to the web industry contracting for clients in Auckland including <u>Zest Media</u> and <u>Brown Paper Bag</u>.

1997 - 2006

Waiter, Bartender, Restaurant Supervisor, Event Manager (Auckland & London)
Various bars & restaurants in Auckland including Horse & Trap, Kermadec, Kings Arms,
Portofino. Also in London: The Feathers (Westminster) and The Jolly Gardeners (Putney).

#### **Technical Skills**

- HTML5 & frameworks: Bootstrap 3, Foundation, Twig, JADE, Mustache
- CSS3: Responsive & cross browser with SASS, LESS, Stylus, Compass
- · Native Javascript with jQuery, AJAX, JSON, Angular, React and much more
- pHp5 & MySQL: LAMP, OOP, Web Services, APIs, SOAP, REST, cURL
- · CMS development in Wordpress, Drupal, Concrete5, Silverstripe, Joomla, Bolt
- MVC Frameworks: Symfony, Laravel, Zend, Codelgniter, CakepHp
- Server administration: Apache, Linux, Nginx, MAMP, WAMP, XAMPP, Plesk, cPanel
- · EDMs, table-based HTML with Campaign Monitor, MailChimp, Litmus, Mandrill
- · App development with Swift, Xcode, Phonegap, Cordova
- Adobe Creative Suite: Photoshop, Fireworks, Illustrator, Dreamweaver, Flash
- · Node.js & Express 4 with noSQL solutions Firebase & MongoDB with Mongoose
- · CLI Tools: SSH, NPM, Composer, Grunt, Gulp, Bundle, Bower, Homebrew
- · Data processing and parsing with JSON, XML, CSV, FPDF
- SEO & Marketing: Google Webmaster Tools & Analytics, Tracking Pixels
- Source control and team tools: Git, Slack, JIRA, Bitbucket, Beanstalk, Basecamp
- · E-Commerce setup and management with Magento, Shopify, WooCommerce
- CDNs, Cloud Services & Social APIs: AWS, Facebook, Twitter, YouTube
- IDEs: Atom, Eclipse, Visual Studio, NetBeans, Sublime Text, Notepad++
- Basic knowledge of Java, Ruby, C, C#, ASP.NET and Flash Actionscript

### Other skills:

- Mastery of English with excellent formal and creative writing skills
- Typing speed of over 80 words per minute
- Over 20 years experience playing guitar and other instruments
- Wit, personality and an appropriate sense of humour

Examples of my work can be found on my website at:

www.graemethornber.com